

Sreeshma S

+971 561186568

<u>sreeprofid@gmail.com</u>

in <u>linkedin.com/in/sreeshma-s</u>

● W4713605

Al NahdaResident Visa

Professional Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 5+ years of experience in developing user friendly and functionally fit webapplications for PoCs and client requirements.

Technical Skills			
Frontend	HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Angular	Backend	Python, Django
Tools	SQL Studio, Git, SonarQube	Database	SQL, Mysql

Employment History

Capgemini Senior Full Stack Developer | Mar 2021 - Sep 2023 | Bangalore

PROJECTS: Building prototypes and working KPI applications for PoC and clients

<u>Tech Stack:</u> Bootstrap, AngularJS, Django <u>Libraries:</u> Plotly, Matplotlib, Pandas, Numpy

Responsibilities included:

- Creating insightful dashboard to present KPI & analytics
- Writing effective queries to serialize ML model outputs
- Building single page, interactive and responsive web pages

CLIENT: Societe Generale Specialist Software Engineer | May 2022 - May 2023 | Bangalore

PROJECTS: Building sophisticated desktop and web apps for investment computation modules

Tech Stack: Django, SQL

<u>Libraries:</u> Pandas, Numpy, SQLAlchemy

Responsibilities included:

- Developing functionalities and exportable reports
- Supporting **ETL tools** to customize data generation
- Working on application dependency configurations for project migration
- Restructuring code for **desktop application** as per hub requirements
- Building test cases and adhering to SonarQube standards

PROJECTS: Building range of full-fledged ERP applications for managing and reporting organizational operations

<u>Tech Stack:</u> Bootstrap, AngularJS, Django

Libraries: ReportLab, FabricJS, ChartJS, Canvas JS, Openpyxl, Seaborn

Responsibilities included:

- Building web APIs using Python Django REST Framework
- Generating PDFs using python ReportLab library
- Representing data insights using chartis and fabricis library

Wizklub Learning

Content Developer | Sep 2018 - Jun 2019 | Bangalore

PROJECTS: Developing content for learning, and supporting automation in scheduling events

Responsibilities included:

- Developing internal ticketing tool using Django & Postgresql
- Developing questions on quantitative aptitude, critical thinking & problem-solving

iTech India Pvt Ltd

Content Developer | Jul 2016 - Aug 2018 | Chennai

PROJECTS: Coordinating with client to promote their businesses with marketing content

Responsibilities included:

- Developing web contents adhering to **SEO principles** for clients
- Creating and publishing company web pages in Wordpress
- Analyzing the social media metrics and *google analytics* to monitor web traffic

Thomas Innovation

Technical Writer | Jan 2015 - Jun 2016 | Chennai

PROJECTS: Creating content for software products and services for documentation purpose

Responsibilities included:

- Understanding product development stages to deliver technical documentation
- Creating algorithms, articles, white papers, and research papers
- Researching various codes & algorithms to process & compute rules of operation

Education

B.E in Electronics and Instrumentation from Jeppiaar Engineering College (Aug 2010 – May 2014)